Why isn't the metro closed if it's not
profitable?  The Moscow metro
operates at a cost of approximately 600 million rubles.  per
day, or 220 billion rubles.  revenue per year.
Last year, they spent around 247 billion rubles on their core business.  That
is, they suffered a net loss of 25 billion
rubles.  And then the question is, why is
n’t such an unprofitable business closed?  In
fact, it's not really a question of money here.
For the city, the metro is a way
to make even more money, but in a
different way.  For example, people
get to work more quickly over a large
area, which means the city produces
more goods.  The company, in turn,
gains access to millions of employees
and clients, which means they
earn more.  Areas near new
metro stations are becoming more expensive, and the budget is receiving more
new taxes.  Moreover, closing the
metro would have a negative impact on motorists.
Millions of passengers would switch to
cars, buses and taxis.  The roads would be
overloaded, and the
city's economic losses would be
greater than the subsidies for
metro maintenance.  Therefore, it is profitable for the state
to pay the metro an additional 25 billion and earn
hundreds of billions in other areas.